Either the most neglected hero in history or a liar of insane proportion!
Little Big Man is a western, comedy, adventure film directed by Arthur Penn.
Jack Crabb, looking back from extreme old age, tells of his life being
raised by Indians and fighting with General Custer.
Jack Crabb, played by Dustin Hoffman.
Mrs. Louise Pendrake, played by Faye Dunaway.
Old Lodge Skins, played by Chief Dan George.
Mr. Merriweather, played by Martin Balsam.
Gen. George Armstrong Custer, played by Richard Mulligan.
Wild Bill Hickok, played by Jeff Corey.
Little Big Man is a 1970 American revisionist Western film directed by Arthur Penn,
adapted by Calder Willingham from Thomas Berger's 1964 novel of the same title.
It stars Dustin Hoffman, Chief Dan George, Faye Dunaway,
Martin Balsam, Jeff Corey and Richard Mulligan.
The film follows the life of a white man who was raised by members of the Cheyenne nation during
the 19th century, and then attempts to reintegrate with American pioneer society.
Although broadly categorized as a Western, or an epic, the film encompasses
several literary/film genres, including comedy, drama and adventure.
It parodies typical tropes of the Western genre, contrasting the lives of white
settlers and Native Americans throughout the progression of the boy's life.
Little Big Man is an early revisionist Western in its sympathetic depiction of Native
Americans, and its exposure of the villainous practices of the United States Cavalry.
The revision uses elements of satire and tragedy to
examine prejudice and injustice.
Little Big Man is an anti-establishment film of the period, indirectly protesting America's
involvement in the Vietnam War by portraying the United States Armed Forces negatively.
The film was released to American theatres by National General Pictures on December
23, 1970, to widespread critical acclaim and commercial success.
Several retrospective reviews have positioned Little Big Man as
one of the best American films of the 1970s.
The film received three BAFTA Award nominations, including
for Best Actor in a Leading Role for Hoffman.
Chief Dan George received an Academy Award nomination for Best Supporting Actor, the
first Indigenous North American actor to be nominated for an Oscar.
In 2014, Little Big Man was deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant" by the
Library of Congress, and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, fight,
indian territory, settler, native american.
The tone is lighthearted.